[{"id": "5ff66f6b52a821ff76ae8b1f", "question": "In Tennessee, it\u2019s illegal to hold office if you\u2019ve done what?", "answer": "Fought in a duel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121b1c63c99d48cd169b0b", "question": "Which gossipy word comes from a sailing term?", "answer": "\"Scuttlebutt\" -- It is the sailing version of office water cooler gossip.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917e", "question": "Who is the voice of Woody in the movie series Toy Story?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adae", "question": "Lady Godiva made her historic ride through what British city?", "answer": "Coventry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b3235b4bf195a31e15d73b2", "question": "What is a system of circulating ocean currents referred to as?", "answer": "A Gyre", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a779", "question": "What body of water does the Colorado river empty into?", "answer": "The Gulf of California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015dedefe83fe1f2a824b73", "question": "How many people died in the Korean War?", "answer": "Two million", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbb", "question": "What model was married to musician Billy Joel?", "answer": "Christie Brinkley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cffe877e98cb97778a59", "question": "What island is located in The Bay of Naples?", "answer": "Capri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad2", "question": "Mila Kunis played what role on \"That '70s Show\"?", "answer": "Jackie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339514", "question": "Who voiced Pinocchio in Disney's 1940 movie by the same name?", "answer": "Dickie Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339185", "question": "What TV show had the tagline: Most gripping sitcom since 1380?", "answer": "The Black Adder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe4", "question": "What two countries share land borders with Tunisia?", "answer": "Algeria and Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afac", "question": "What was Sunday, January 30th 1972, generally remembered as in Ireland?", "answer": "Bloody Sunday", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8fbb801dd7bf43be5e854", "question": "A traditional Greyhound cocktail is made with vodka, or gin, and what else?", "answer": "Grapefruit juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febae847e83c707845b20f6", "question": "Which insect uses the Milky Way to navigate?", "answer": "African dung beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab68", "question": "In what Australian state would you find the major port town Fremantle?", "answer": "Western Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a358", "question": "What South American city does an 82 foot statue of Christ overlook?", "answer": "Rio de Janeiro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca37", "question": "Which element is third on the periodic table?", "answer": "Lithium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a3", "question": "Before the vowel shift of the middle ages, how would the English pronounce \"Mickey Mouse\"?", "answer": "Mickey Moose", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b089", "question": "When was the Hubble telescope launched into orbit?", "answer": "April 24, 1990", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b7d", "question": "Who is best known for his painting \"American Gothic\"?", "answer": "Grant Wood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64a", "question": "What does a Scoville unit measure?", "answer": "Spiciness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59067e76ff9c0647b50a807a", "question": "Who was awarded the 2016 Nobel Prize for Literature?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd26", "question": "What Bruins and Rangers legend founded the Tampa Bay Lightning in 1991?", "answer": "Phil Esposito", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7bf10877e98cb97778965", "question": "What is the smallest country in South America?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a167", "question": "Who played Sarah Conner in the 1991 film \"Terminator 2: Judgment Day\"?", "answer": "Linda Hamilton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be580225415ba52ed6f0ab1", "question": "The TV show \"Soap\", was set in what fictional town?", "answer": "Dunn's River, Connecticut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a3", "question": "Ascorbic acid is commonly referred to as what?", "answer": "Vitamin C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae4", "question": "Havana is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fa", "question": "What is the common name for the fruit Citrus grandis?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e6b28dfb6c85e9e634ff3f", "question": "Which years did Henry VI reign England?", "answer": "1422 to 1461 and 1470 to 1471", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af75", "question": "What treaty ended the Mexican War?", "answer": "Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba29", "question": "What was the original name of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "Liberty Enlightening the World", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76d", "question": "What lake in Oregon was created about 7,000 years ago by the eruption of Mount Mazama?", "answer": "Crater Lake", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51301ff04d658268c92d5", "question": "Where was Adolf Hitler born?", "answer": "Hitler was born in Braunau am Inn, a town in Austria-Hungary (present-day Austria)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea5", "question": "What takes its name from the Japanese for \"whimsical pictures\"?", "answer": "Manga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae51", "question": "In what ship did the Pilgrims sail to the New World in 1620?", "answer": "Mayflower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7d04e877e98cb97778a5e", "question": "What is the capital of Newfoundland and Labrador?", "answer": "St. John's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede60a6ce05a3942286df4", "question": "On what avenue does the traditional New York City Easter Parade and Bonnet Festival take place?", "answer": "Fifth Avenue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2fa", "question": "Who played the role of Grant in the 1966 film \"Fantastic Voyage\"?", "answer": "Stephen Boyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecca88ec223966ae8f889a", "question": "In American football, the area behind the line of scrimmage is known as what?", "answer": "The backfield", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c13c", "question": "With which instrument is jazz musician Charlie Mingus principally associated?", "answer": "Double Bass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96e4523c87fd04dd15e35", "question": "What did Shakespeare leave his wife in his will?", "answer": "His second-best bed", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b04e", "question": "Which U.S. President signed the National Aeronautics and Space Act establishing NASA?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339648", "question": "What was the nickname of Gene Hackman's character in The French Connection?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e3", "question": "What was the middle name of composer Bach?", "answer": "Sebastian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6008dd47f4f3bc4a292f861f", "question": "When was the last time when the U.S officially declared war?", "answer": "June 5, 1942", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c88e", "question": "What does the Kardashev scale measure?", "answer": "Energy available to alien civilizations", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e72ce4cd0874f1a5e2d1c27", "question": "Which prominent US statesman was known as \"The Great Compromiser\" and helped allegedly swing the 1824 election?", "answer": "Henry Clay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd81", "question": "With what team did Dennis Rodman win his first NBA title?", "answer": "The Detroit Pistons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5941257abab1e6f9796f1b54", "question": "Which character is always trying to steal the secret Krusty Krab Recipe on \"SpongeBob SquarePants\"?", "answer": "Plankton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a61902ebb971c1417fb88", "question": "How many hurdles are there in a 400 metres hurdle race?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc0", "question": "What mythical bird dies in flames and is reborn from the ashes?", "answer": "Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5906820bff9c0647b50a8099", "question": "Who was the male lead in the 1976 film \"The Man Who Fell to Earth\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31b", "question": "Who played the role of Jack Tripper on the TV show \"Three's Company\"?", "answer": "John Ritter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cc26bb53d1af658864de", "question": "Which singer sang \"I Believe in Father Christmas\"?", "answer": "Greg Lake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c11", "question": "In what year was comedian Stephen Colbert born?", "answer": "1964", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f13", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Cate Blanchett and Judi Dench?", "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f089ff048f679a45aa9e", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb9c67e83c707845b213f", "question": "What do you call someone who studies sea shells?", "answer": "Conchologist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66c41a5bfecdd737e0891", "question": "What country is said to be the world\u2019s leading manufacturer of false teeth?", "answer": "Liechtenstein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e46", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"The Scorpion King\"?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903b", "question": "Which musical term denotes that a piece is to be played \"sweetly\"?", "answer": "Dolce", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad47", "question": "Harry Truman was known as \"the Haberdasher\" because of what?", "answer": "His previous occupation", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c000", "question": "Which vegetable is used if a dish is described as \"a la Crecy\"?", "answer": "Carrots", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cdac8e347d002c297e4d7", "question": "What instrument did Yehudi Menuhin play?", "answer": "The violin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d1", "question": "When facing Mount Rushmore, which president's head is farthest to your left?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a57", "question": "The 2006 Mel Gibson movie \"Apocalypto\" concerns the demise of what ancient empire?", "answer": "The Mayan Empire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada3", "question": "Who was better known as Butch Cassidy?", "answer": "Robert Leroy Parker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65dd01f3c0ead6880d622", "question": "According to the Bible, where was Jesus crucified?", "answer": "Golgotha", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339892", "question": "Who did Johnny Carson replace as host of \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Jack Paar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b17", "question": "Who wielded a sword named Excalibur?", "answer": "King Arthur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b064", "question": "The \"CSS Hunley\" was the first of what type of vessel to sink an enemy ship?", "answer": "Submarine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70c", "question": "In the Christmas song, The Holly and The Ivy which one bears the crown?", "answer": "The holly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5f8f6ce05a3942286e44", "question": "What was the original name of the Boston Red Sox?", "answer": "Boston Americans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5921fcdca4edfd43a087adc3", "question": "What number is represented by \"V\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "5", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b12f01dd7bf43be5e790", "question": "Where was the first drive in movie theater?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb3", "question": "Who was head coach of the Notre Dame college football team from 1918 to 1930?", "answer": "Knute Rockne", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde9", "question": "Shechita is the method of producing meat that is what?", "answer": "Kosher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a0", "question": "What is Ethiopia's main commercial crop?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338940", "question": "What do the boys use to start a signal fire in the book \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "Piggy's glasses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8df", "question": "What describes a person with no skin pigment?", "answer": "An Albino", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbd509000d154d7af00b8d7", "question": "Tom DeLonge, Mark Hoppus and Scott Raynor formed which band?", "answer": "Blink-182", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f9", "question": "In the 1986 movie \"Labyrinth\", what disguise does the King of the Goblins visits Sarah's house under?", "answer": "An owl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf1", "question": "The Albert Canal links Liege with which city?", "answer": "Antwerp", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76e9beec85e375820b2de", "question": "What is the biggest country without a river?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb667e5dad637d903c8837", "question": "The Hunua Ranges is located where?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a2", "question": "Who wrote the book \"A Brief History of Time'' In 1988?\u00a0", "answer": "Stephen Hawking\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a957", "question": "Which European country replaced the Drachma with the Euro?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339873", "question": "In Disney's \"Alice in Wonderland\", who is the companion of The Walrus?", "answer": "A Carpenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e94527ccba3ffe45786d2", "question": "What year was the element Californium first synthesized?", "answer": "1950", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc3f26ce05a3942286f29", "question": "Colin Hay is the founder and lead vocalist for what rock band?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b987", "question": "In which year was the wearing of seat belts made compulsory in the UK?", "answer": "1983", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339955", "question": "What was Norm\u2019s last name on the TV show \"Cheers\"?", "answer": "Peterson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab95d686faa38a764be519", "question": "Under what name was the AC Cobra sold in the US?", "answer": "Shelby Cobra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe90a4701dd7bf43be5e899", "question": "Which element, previously used in the production of felt, lead to the expression \"mad as a hatter\"?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fde4eb3c6c6b019850c9a86", "question": "What was eBay.com originally called?", "answer": "AuctionWeb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecdd33ec223966ae8f8901", "question": "What comedian did Henry take Karen to see in the movie \"Goodfellas\"?", "answer": "Henny Youngman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf90", "question": "What was unusual about Tyrell's car in the 1976 Swedish Grand Prix?", "answer": "It had six wheels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca46", "question": "In the body what may be endocrine or exocrine?", "answer": "Glands", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f3", "question": "Cushat, Rock and Stock all types of which creature?", "answer": "Doves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b370d21c3f17ccc40c8e19", "question": "Under the English 1830 Beer Act, what was the cost of the licence to sell beer and cider from your own home?", "answer": "2 guineas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e4", "question": "What was Higgins first name in the TV show \"Magnum PI\"?", "answer": "Jonathan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7decff048f679a45ac02", "question": "Aphenphosmphobia is fear of what?", "answer": "Being touched", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2157531a458464a93c45f", "question": "What is the name given to people who make arrows?", "answer": "Fletcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fcc", "question": "Which writer coined the word \"Cyberspace\"?", "answer": "William Gibson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c39", "question": "What is the name of the cafe in the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Central Perk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339490", "question": "Anthony Hopkins played a ventriloquist in which 1978 movie?", "answer": "Magic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173bcf44491cbd7c5a17a0", "question": "The words of poet Emma Lazarus are on which U.S. monument?", "answer": "Her line, \"Give me your tired, your poor, your huddled masses yearning to breathe free,\" are on the base of the Statue of Liberty.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f0", "question": "What unit of land measurement equals 43,560 square feet?", "answer": "An acre", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940e", "question": "The 1997 movie \"Dante's Peak\" tells the story of a town that is threatened by what?", "answer": "A volcano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60a", "question": "What is an alloy?", "answer": "A metal mixed with an element", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada6", "question": "The \"Italian Plague of 1629-31\" is also referred to as by what other name?", "answer": "Great Plague of Milan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb2", "question": "What US state has a Thames River?", "answer": "Connecticut", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec83ccec223966ae8f87f9", "question": "The late Michael Jackson is widely known as the \"King of Pop\". But who is considered the \"Queen of Pop\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66d87a5bfecdd737e08a2", "question": "What is the most littered item in the U.S.?", "answer": "Cigarette butts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d015bb53d1af658864f8", "question": "Who directed the 1946 film \"It\u2019s a Wonderful Life\"?", "answer": "Frank Capra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b299", "question": "Who was the only slave ever known to have stayed in Thomas Jefferson's household?", "answer": "Sally Hemings", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cadc", "question": "What is the offspring of a male horse and a female donkey?", "answer": "A Hinny", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95c", "question": "The Purple Heart is awarded for which reason?", "answer": "For wounds received by enemy action while on active service", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db8", "question": "Which member of the Bee Gees played no instruments on stage?", "answer": "Robin Gibb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db77d30ab2c8f322317fef", "question": "What country does motor racing's Jacques Villeneuve come from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e9750ebfabb9c85d8a963", "question": "What was Ben Stiller's character called in the 1999 film \"Mystery Men\"?", "answer": "Mr. Furious", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa3ce6ce05a3942286eaa", "question": "Which of the Beach Boys actually knew how to surf?", "answer": "Dennis Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e1b6e748bb36357acdf6", "question": "Who is the singer behind the albums \"1989\" and \"Reputation\"?", "answer": "Taylor Swift", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57b", "question": "US city Milwaukee is located on the shores of what lake?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad0", "question": "What rock group took its name from the chief river of Hades in Greek mythology?", "answer": "Styx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904a538cf93664eb10486c9", "question": "Including spin-offs and tie-ins, how many issues were released as part of the original \"Strangers in Paradise\" comic series before its planned end in 2007?", "answer": "106", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebe", "question": "Whose series of thirteen children's books of thirteen chapters each ended in 2006 with \"The End\"?", "answer": "Lemony Snicket's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b528", "question": "What does the beer widget do?", "answer": "Manages the beer's head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a477", "question": "How many South American Countries does the equator pass through?", "answer": "Three", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d118314fea7fe947a22282", "question": "Which part of the body is dermatology concerned with?", "answer": "The skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa59", "question": "Tenerife is the largest island in which archipelago?", "answer": "Canary Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5f1b6ce05a3942286e3d", "question": "Elton John wrote the song \"Philadelphia Freedom\" as a tribute to what tennis star?", "answer": "Billie Jean King", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c704fbde8045e48466bc", "question": "What does \"Homo sapiens\" mean?", "answer": "Wise man -- Biological classifier Carolus Linnaeus declared us \"Homo sapiens\", which translates from Latin to \"wise man\".", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1a", "question": "What author created Prydain?", "answer": "Lloyd Alexander", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a390", "question": "Where in London are the Crown Jewels kept?", "answer": "The Tower of London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc2", "question": "What country borders Albania to the south?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c74d", "question": "In 1993, what name did Intel give to its new 80586 line of chips?", "answer": "Pentium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad9", "question": "Who created the \"Spy vs Spy\" silent comic strip?", "answer": "Antonio Prohias", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f42", "question": "What song is, appropriately , attributed to a seventeenth-century composer, Dr. John Bull?", "answer": "God Save the King/Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c3", "question": "What is the capital of South Korea?", "answer": "Seoul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bfe00fcb668d7dfe168b5c7", "question": "When did Napoleon Bonaparte begin his reign as Emperor of the French?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56f", "question": "Which Australian animal has unique fingerprints?", "answer": "Koala", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6000ecbf9a72b906b34e3ce5", "question": "How is the groundnut better known?", "answer": "Peanut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339329", "question": "In \"The Godfather\", who plays Michael Corleone?", "answer": "Al Pacino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774295284458f1d7854421", "question": "What contestant-based reality television series aired in the United States originated in Holland?", "answer": "The Voice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba323874c93a3298b2138", "question": "Which French composer wrote the symphonic poem \"The Sorcerer's Apprentice\"?", "answer": "Paul Dukas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cf", "question": "Who directed the 2007 sci-fi movie \"Sunshine\"?", "answer": "Danny Boyle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f200ff048f679a45aab5", "question": "What type of cloud is characterized by thin, wispy strands?", "answer": "Cirrus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ca3f1e44f0f6af5b066650", "question": "Morello is a variety of which fruit?", "answer": "Cherry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af25190b63e5727cf5a4839", "question": "By what name do Germans refer to Austria?", "answer": "\u04e6sterreich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17a", "question": "What object is said to bring bad luck if it is broken?", "answer": "Mirror", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062be2c9d816e292245c26", "question": "Which Henri Matisse painting was hung upside down at the Museum of Modern Art in New York for 46 days without anyone noticing?", "answer": "Le Bateau (\"The Boat\"), a paper-cut, caused a stir in 1961 when the Museum of Modern Art in New York hung the work upside-down.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69c6520565ad31a57c76b", "question": "Who was the first African-American to be featured on a U.S. postage stamp?", "answer": "Booker T. Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d08381a1c922dd1ac64c1", "question": "Nordic and Alpine are two main genres of which sport?", "answer": "Skiing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f167cdf7c52aae91cc07be", "question": "The Bijagos Archipelago lie off which country's mainland?", "answer": "Guinea-Bissau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe937f36bd93ce3a4e5f67c", "question": "Hemophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Blood", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996e", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Principal Skinner's mother?", "answer": "Agnes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b22", "question": "What is the name of the little people in \"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Munchkins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa5623c73aa70ea0b70b28", "question": "In which state of the United States would you find Fort Knox?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bb35ac72627b8fe95581be9", "question": "In what country was Mel Gibson born?", "answer": "United States", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe000791cf6db9ac4808d12", "question": "What are the Philippines named after?", "answer": "Spain's King Philip II", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac45", "question": "What does the Russian space station's name \"Mir\" mean in English?", "answer": "Peace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade3", "question": "What was Liu Bang, founder of the Han Dynasty, posthumously known as?", "answer": "Emperor Gaozu of Han", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5b", "question": "In 1995, Heather Whitestone became the first Miss America to have what disability?", "answer": "She was deaf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b307", "question": "On what island is King Arthur buried?", "answer": "Avalon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09f", "question": "How many wine gallons does a \"half pipe\" barrel contain?", "answer": "63", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e94d2015ea27d7a1303aed7", "question": "In what US state is the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa5611c73aa70ea0b70b27", "question": "In which country is May Day the only holiday workers are obliged to be given the day off yet still be paid for it?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe7", "question": "How many players are in a Polo team?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe775cceec85e375820b311", "question": "What U.S. city has an airport named after a President and First Lady?", "answer": "Little Rock, Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339253", "question": "What rocker's song \"Rock Is Dead\" is heard in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Marilyn Manson's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a169", "question": "In the film \"The Day of the Jackal\", who did Edward Fox play?", "answer": "Jackal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394dd", "question": "What kind of animals are \"Pinky and the Brain\"?", "answer": "Lab mice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c52ffbde8045e48466a8", "question": "What characteristic is unique to cetacean creatures?", "answer": "A blowhole -- Cetaceans (whales, porpoises, and dolphins)  use the blowhole on top of their head to breath oxygen.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c2c5877e98cb9777898d", "question": "What city was known as and almost permanently named \"Batmania\"?", "answer": "Melbourne, Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f16a6bf7c52aae91cc07dc", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\", who is Alonso's son?", "answer": "Ferdinand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc1fbec223966ae8f8871", "question": "What singer was born in Havana in 1957, the daughter of a bodyguard employed by dictator Fulgencio Batista?", "answer": "Gloria Estefan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbf", "question": "Which two public figures were assassinated in the United States in 1968?", "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr. and Robert Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cefc1e1948005ec986edce8", "question": "Most frequently, full extraction of coffee's flavor occurs when water reaches what temperature?", "answer": "195\u00b0F", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03a", "question": "Where is the Popliteal Fossa located?", "answer": "Back of the knee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe73efdeec85e375820b277", "question": "Which archipelago means \"sheep islands\"?", "answer": "Faroe Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c257", "question": "In the computer world, what does the abbreviation RAM stand for?", "answer": "Random Access Memory", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53f", "question": "What letter is least used in the English language?", "answer": "Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b5", "question": "What trumpeter is considered the pioneer of cool jazz?", "answer": "Miles Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66bcea5bfecdd737e0889", "question": "Which espresso drink is named for a religious order?", "answer": "Cappuccino", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338886", "question": "Who devoured a cake with the words \"Eat Me\" written on it in currants?", "answer": "Alice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d9", "question": "What was the name of Dr. Evil\u2019s cat in the \"Austin Powers\" movies series?", "answer": "Mr. Bigglesworth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c5", "question": "What was Mr. Seaver's first name on the TV show \"Growing Pains\"?", "answer": "Jason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e90fb89d7247dfc0fa00306", "question": "From the anime \"Fairy Tail\" who is known to be Titania, The Queen of Fairies?", "answer": "Erza Scarlet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c753", "question": "What scale is used to measure the hardness of minerals?", "answer": "The Mohs Scale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910c", "question": "What nationality was writer, neurologist and psychiatrist Viktor E. Frankl?", "answer": "Austrian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133902f", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Vulcan?", "answer": "Hephaestos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911c", "question": "Who wrote the 1910 novel \"Howards End\"?", "answer": "E. M. Forster", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6aa4820565ad31a57c814", "question": "Who first developed stereophonic sound?", "answer": "Alan Blumlein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad9daf9e748bb36357acdd6", "question": "What is the name of the bony covering over the gills of ray-finned fishes?", "answer": "Operculum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fedddfd6ce05a3942286da9", "question": "Which popular candy was featured prominently in the classic film \"E.T., the Extra-Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "Hershey Company's Reece's Pieces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0fc", "question": "Who created Gomez, Mortia and Uncle Fester as a cartoon?", "answer": "Charles Addams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a220", "question": "Which tough guy actor was once a linotype operator?", "answer": "Robert Mitchum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ff", "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b128", "question": "What does the seventh amendment of the US Constitution guarantee?", "answer": "Trial by Jury", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e87", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Faun?", "answer": "Human and goat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c77cf0f24f0f7a362efd54b", "question": "In the first Super Mario Bros. game, in which level is the first three-world secret exit?", "answer": "World 1-2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3de", "question": "What city is the capital of Turkey?", "answer": "Ankara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e5dffe83fe1f2a824bc6", "question": "Who was \"The Lady Bandit of Arizona\"?", "answer": "Pearl Hart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948f", "question": "How long did the 1929 Academy Award ceremony last?", "answer": "15 minutes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b18d", "question": "What year was astronaut Neil Armstrong born?", "answer": "1930", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c9f7b1b4e2c7fbd389674b", "question": "How is a Long black coffee different from an Americano?", "answer": "The espresso is poured on top of the hot water, instead of before", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b320", "question": "Who became prime minister of Cuba in 1959?\u00a0", "answer": "Fidel Castro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b1", "question": "What large island is the most western point of land in Alaska?", "answer": "Attu Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888b", "question": "Where was King Arthur's court?", "answer": "Camelot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbe076ce05a3942286ee6", "question": "In what western television series did Richard Boone star?", "answer": "Have Gun - Will Travel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd1", "question": "Who was the beautiful youth loved by the Greek goddess Aphrodite?", "answer": "Adonis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897d", "question": "What was Long John Silver's parrot Captain Flint favorite phrase?", "answer": "Pieces of eight", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f7", "question": "What was the first name of the cartoon character Mr. Magoo?", "answer": "Quincy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bcc", "question": "What did God create on the fourth day?", "answer": "The Sun, the Moon and the Stars", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390df", "question": "In which play does Dame Pliant appear?", "answer": "The Alchemist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b62", "question": "What broadcast television network debuted on October 9, 1986?", "answer": "FOX", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a822", "question": "When facing Mount Rushmore, which president's head is farthest to your left?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded33fea2747c8aff16d46", "question": "What type of a clothing item is a \"Sam Browne\"?", "answer": "A belt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a345", "question": "What role did Anna Faris play in the 2000 film \"Scary Movie\"?", "answer": "Cindy Campbell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a252", "question": "What 1980s TV show starred Bruce Willis in a detective agency?", "answer": "Moonlighting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde5129c6c6b019850c9a8d", "question": "Who was the first King of the Northern Ten Tribes of Israel during the time of the Divided Kingdom?", "answer": "Jeroboam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b873", "question": "What company did Craig Newmark found?", "answer": "Craigslist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c7", "question": "Hurricane season in the North Atlantic officially begins on the first day of what month?", "answer": "June", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f74bca9e54d890926f6fe", "question": "What was banned in Indonesia for \"stimulating passion\"?", "answer": "Hula hoops", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339856", "question": "Totoro from the movie \"My Neighbor Totoro\" can make plants grow extra fast by doing what?", "answer": "Dancing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae16", "question": "Which European country invaded Libya in 1911?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f42001dd7bf43be5e81e", "question": "In computers, DAEMON stands for what?", "answer": "Disk And Execution Monitor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa416fc73aa70ea0b70b0f", "question": "Which Hawaiian island is entirely privately owned?", "answer": "Ni'ihau (The island was purched by wealthy Scottish plantation owners from King Kamehameha V in 1864 for $10,000 in gold.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a5", "question": "What NFLer was nickname the \"Minister of Defense\"?", "answer": "Reggie White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c42f", "question": "What is the longest and heaviest bone in the human body?", "answer": "Femur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173f8044491cbd7c5a17b2", "question": "Who was the first woman to cross the English Channel?", "answer": "Harriet Quimby flew across the English Channel in 1912.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339928", "question": "What was the name of Phoebe\u2019s twin sister on \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Ursula", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a48d", "question": "By what name is the Thames known as it passes through Oxford?", "answer": "The Isis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2c", "question": "What novel by Lucy Maud Montgomery became Canada's longest-running main stage musical?", "answer": "Anne of Green Gables", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b779", "question": "How many holes are there in a standard Ritz cracker?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5ab55dad637d903c8818", "question": "What is the world's largest national park?", "answer": "Northeast Greenland National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339788", "question": "How many copies must a recording sell to be designated multi-platinum?", "answer": "2 million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339671", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who hit Bart with his car?", "answer": "Mr. Burns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde492cc6c6b019850c9a6c", "question": "According to the Bible, what prophet was killed by being sawed in two inside a hollow log?", "answer": "Isaiah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b6", "question": "Which English city was actor Stephen Fry born in?", "answer": "London", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba239874c93a3298b2130", "question": "Who wasn't afraid to call James Joyce \"a greasy undergraduate\"?", "answer": "Virginia Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f08c01dd7bf43be5e7fe", "question": "What is the key difference between pizza and flatbread?", "answer": "Yeast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d71b2b42d4a3561a9f0a", "question": "On what American network were you able to watch the TV show \u201cThe Beatles\u201d from 1965 until 1969?", "answer": "ABC", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d81", "question": "Whose paintings include \"The Red Room\", \"The Green Stripe\", \"The Blue Nudes\" and \"The Yellow Odalisque\"?", "answer": "Henri Matisse's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e8", "question": "Carlos Irwin Est\u00e9vez is best known by what stage name?", "answer": "Charlie Sheen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d91", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Clifford Harris?", "answer": "T.I.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e8", "question": "On what holiday did W. C. Fields die?", "answer": "Christmas Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae864e27f28483af1e7fdcf", "question": "In the 2016 film \"The Founder\" who plays Ray Kroc, who helped franchise McDonald\u2019s?", "answer": "Michael Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}]